A for loop lets your program repeat some instructions a certain number of times.
For 循环允许程序重复某些指示次数
It also let's those instructions use values taken from a list,
它还让这些指令使用从列表中获取的值
but what goes inside a for loop can actually be pretty complex,
但里面的东西其实很复杂
it can even include other loops.
它甚至可以包括其它的环路
If a loop that runs five times is inside a loop that runs six times,
如果运行 5 次的循环在运行 6 次的循环中
then the inner code will run five times six, equals 30 times.
那么内部代码会运行五次六 等于 30 次
So, for example, here's our familiar loop that
例如 这是我们熟悉的循环
draws a square and here's another one that draws a smaller square.
画一个正方形 另一个则画一个更小的正方形
It's exactly the same except the turtle goes forward ten pixels each time instead of 100.
除了海龟外 每个时间的 10 像素都是一样的 而不是 100
Now, I can take this loop and put it inside the other one.
现在 我可以把这个回路 放在另一个回路里
All I have to do is indent it like this.
我要做的就是把它缩进去
This is called a nested loop.
这称为嵌套循环
We'd say that this loop is nested inside this loop.
我们会说这个循环嵌套在这个循环中
So if we run this code,
所以如果我们运行这个代码
it draws one side of the big square then it enters
它从大广场的一侧画出来
the nested loop and draws all four sides of the smaller square.
嵌套环 并绘制较小的正方形的四周
Then it goes back to the top of the big loop and draws the next big side.
然后它又回到大环的顶端 画下一个大的一面
Then it goes into the nested loop and draws
然后它进入嵌套循环并绘制
another small square and so on until it's all done.
另一个小广场等一切都结束了
All in all, we ran this main loop
总之 我们运行了这个主回路
four times and we ran this nested loop four times for each time the main loop ran.
四次 每次主回路运行时 我们都运行了四次嵌套循环
So, that's four times four or 16 times in total.
这一共是四倍  16 倍
Okay. So, that's the idea of a nested loop.
好吧好吧 这是一个嵌套循环的想法
Let's look at a little more of an interesting example.
让我们再看看一个有趣的例子
Here is another example of a nested loop.
下面是嵌套循环的另一个示例
This code is going to draw a chain made of hexagons like this.
这个代码将会绘制一条由六边形这样的六边形组成的链
First, we say there will be eight links in the chain and six sides on a hexagon.
首先 我们说链条中有八条链接 六边是六边形
So, we set up some variables with the list of eight and the list of six.
所以 我们设置了一些变量 列出了 8 个和 6个列表
We'll loop over these variables with an outer loop that runs once for
我们将使用运行一次的外环来循环这些变量
each link in the chain and an inner loop that runs once for each side of those links.
链中的每个链接以及每个链接的每个边运行一次的内部循环
So for link in links,
链接中的链接
we draw one hexagon then scoot over to the next link which we do
我们绘制一个六边形然后再到下一个链接
by picking the pen up moving forward and putting the pen back down again.
拿起笔向前移 再把笔放下
To draw one hexagon,
要绘制一个六边形
we do the inner loop.
我们做内部循环
For side insides, in other words for each of the six sides,
对双方来说 换句话说 对于六方的每一方来说
we go forward by 10 and right by 60.
我们前进 10 到 60
So, this inner loop makes
所以这个内环
one hexagon and the rest of this code inside the outer loop moves
外循环中的一个六边形和另一个代码
from one link to the next.
从一个链接到下一个链接
All in all, this code draws this whole chain.
总之 这个代码绘制了整个链条
Now you can modify this code to draw a different pattern.
现在 您可以修改此代码以绘制不同的模式
Make whatever pattern you like. Here's an example.
你喜欢什么花样 这是一个例子